Guide to the Frank K. Tittel Academic and Personal Papers, 1987-1997 UA 394
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Frank K. Tittel Academic and Personal Papers
1987-1997
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Tittel, Frank K.
UA 394
1 Linear Feet 1 box
The collection consists of papers relating to the Rice Quantum Institute, laser and laser fusion studies, articles and personal papers. Professor Tittel was a guest of the 1996 Nobel Prize investiture of his associates Robert Curl and Richard Smalley and his mementos of the occasion are included.
Biographical / Historical
Frank K. Tittel, J.S. Abercrombie Professor of Electrical and Computer Engineering, and chair of the department, was born in Germany in 1933 and studies physics at Oxford University, England, receiving his PhD from Oxford in 1959. He came to the United States in 1959 and to Rice University in 1967. In addition to his teaching skills, he was considered one of the nation's top authorities on the applications of lasers.
Scope and Contents
The holding consists of papers relating to the Rice Quantum Institute, laser and laser fusion studies, articles and personal papers. Professor Tittel was a guest of the 1996 Nobel Prize investiture of his associates Robert Curl and Richard Smalley and his mementos of the occasion are included.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Index Terms
Subjects
Education; Chemical engineering -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges
Places
Rice University
- Series I: Personal
  - Curriculum vitae with list of publications (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographic information and related papers (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Department chairmanship, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual report to the President on scholarly activities, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board of Co-Editors-special fields, "Applied Physics" (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Data for "American Men & Women of Science", 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Rice Engineering Alumni certificate of recognition, 1994-04-16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Nobel Prize related, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - U.S.-Hungary Cooperative Science Program, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Welch Foundation lecture, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Welch Foundation annual reports, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Society of Photo-Optical Instrumentation Engineers (SPIE) papers, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Series II: Rice Quantum Institute papers
  - Publicity (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - First Annual Summer Research Colloquium, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Departmental/administrative, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Activities, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Legal, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Presentation, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Application for federal assistance, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Series III: Laser-related
  - Subseries A: Lectures/presentations
    - "Laser Technology in the Eighties," Rice Associates luncheon, 1982-11-30 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - "The Light Fantastic," Provost's lecture, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - "Progress in Excimer Laser Technology and Applications" (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - "New Opportunities in Infrared Laser Spectroscopy" (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Conferences (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Subseries B: Papers authored/co-authored by Tittel
    - "Spectroscopy and Kinetic Reactions of NeF and Ne2F" (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - "Excimer Laser Technology and Applications" (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - "Nonlinear Optical Frequency Conversion Techniques" (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - "Laser Assisted Epitaxial Growth of II-VI Semiconductor Compounds" (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - "Laser-Induced Autofluorescence: A New Medical Imaging Technique for Diagnosis of the Arterial Wall" (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Various (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Subseries C: Laser-related
    - Laser fusion (Box 1, Folder 32-35)
    - "Laser-designated Photoionization of Barium for the Production of a 71.2 nm Laser" (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Laser treatment of kidney stones (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - "Solid State Excimers" (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - "Genuflectron Time-of-flight Mass Spectrometer" (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - "Collisionally Excited Rubidium as an VUX/XUV Coherent Source" (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - "Alkali-Halide Excimers" (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - "Ionic Alkali Halide Excimers Excited by Laser Produced Plasmas" (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - "Spectroscopic Studies of C2H and C2D using a Color Center Laser" (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - "Kinetic Studies Using a Color Center Laser Spectrometer" (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Randal G. Hulet materials (Box 1, Folder 45)